STEPHEN K. SENFT

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



615-456-8619



stephensenft21@gmail.com

Greater Nashvillle Area



www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-senft



https://github.com/stephensenft21

PERSONAL PROFILE

II am a friendly Nashville native and an extrovert with a passion for learning new skillsets. As an incredible career in the restaurant industry came to an end, I began to search for new opportunities. I discovered Nashville Software School through a conversation with a close friend and NSS alumni. I began to explore the idea of software development as a future opportunity. I saw the many possibilities to grow in a new fulfilling career which led to my decision to enroll in Nashville Software School.

Within the subsequent six months I learned technologies like; HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node, React.js, Git, Source Controle, Grunt, Webpack, Visual Studio, Figma, Canva, Google, Asp.net, ADO.net, Entity, PHP, Jquery, .Net, C# MySQL, Restful API. Familiar with backend server-side development concepts, test-driven development, pair programming, source code control in a team environment, rubber ducking, common code patterns following strict naming conventions. Now that I've graduated I continue to write code to stay sharp as a software developer. I have personally built two applications with the technologies listed above. I've also worked on several team-oriented projects which are reflected in my Github repositories.

When I am not coding I keep myself busy playing various team sports, staying fit in the gym, swimming, and rock-climbing. Despite leaving the restaurant industry My love for food and cooking hasn't diminished. I enjoy stretching my creative muscles mastering unique dishes in the kitchen. I am looking forward to working in a team environment, growing my skills and becoming an integral part of the Nashville tech community.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School, Full-stack Developer FEB 2019 - PRESENT

- 6-month apprenticeship program focusing on front end development projects in a technical environment that includes: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3, Git, Github, npm.
- Front-End focused software development boot camp emphasizing modern technologies including Javascript, HTML, CSS, React, Flexbox, Firebase, and Node.js
- Team centered and pair-programming focused sprints to complete increasingly elaborate CRUD applications consuming unique APIs.
- Present single-page applications using both vanilla Javascript and React.
- Consumed external APIs and built out ERDs for data architecture with a REST API via JSON Server.
- Utilized Flexbox, Grid for UX/UI layout & styling.
- Team based projects with agile sprints, pair-programming, issue tracking, stories, and retrospectives
- Gained experience with source and version control with Git and GitHub
- Built Full-stack Application in a team of 4 using ADO.net, MVC, SQL server, Bootstrap, CSS. This application solved a problem allowing HR to on-board new employees. show employee information, assign a computer to employee and assign training programs to the employee if necessary.
- Team-based project using scrum methodologies. Web API built using C# ADO.net, SQL Server, DB diagram, Git, This project was a long challenging one where we had to make specific endpoints for our front end developers to retrieve and manipulate data.

PROJECTS

NOCD

First Cake https://github.com/stephensenft21/First-Cake

React-based mobile first single page application that helps users find casual date spots in the Nashville area. Used Zomato's API to get current data of the location. Users are able to save favorite locations, add comments with full-CRUD functionality and delete favorite locations. Implemented functional components using some React Hooks to effect the state of the views.

https://github.com/stephensenft21/Back-end-Capstone-NameUndecided-

Fullstack application built using a React Client, C# ASP.NET Entity Framework, Identity, SQL Server, , Chart.js Material UI, CSS for styling. Db diagram for data architecture. This app is designed to help therapists and their patients keep track of the short term and long term progress of a particular type of therapy for patients with Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder. The most common practice is Cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT), a type of psychotherapy, that is effective for many people with OCD. . This app will allow the patient to collect day to day data after they are exposed to what triggers their OCD and how they handle the situation.

SKILLS

TECH

- Javascript
- HTML 5
- CSS
- React.js
- React Hooks Enitity
- Webpack • React Chart.js • ADO.NET

Bootstrap

ASP.NET

- C# / .NET Moment.is
- Json Server
 Identity

DESIGN

- Canva
- Figma
- Adobe XD
- Db Diagram
- Material UI
- Reactstrap
- Mogups

SYSTEMS

• SQL Express • Rest API

- Microsoft Office
- Visual Studio Code

GRUNT

NPM

- Google
- Quick Books
- Excel
- OpenTable

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Full-Stack Software Developer (2019) NASM Certificate in Sports Medicine (2016) **Volunteer State Community College** Sports Medicine (2014-2016) Food Handler Certifications (State of Tn)

WORK EXPERIENCE

FEB 2012 - 2019 Melting Pot, Resturant Manager

- Maximize guest satisfaction by maintaining a high standard among all FOH and BOH service staff
- Ensured a safe working and guest environment to reduce the risk of injury and accidents
- Created fun team building competitions to motivate staff to meet revenue targets and identify up-sale opportunities
- Correctly calculated inventory and ordered appropriate supplies.
- · Carefully selected individuals for hire, using structured interviewing techniques
- Responsible for hiring, on-boarding and skillful terminations for all staff
- Professionally interacted with product vendors negotiating product prices suitable for the business's quarterly budget
- Supervised and maintained a group of team-leads instructing new staff and upholding company policies
- Oversaw front of house personnel to maintain adequate staffing and minimize overtime

FEB 2013 - FEB 2015 Bartender - Lead

- Maximize guest satisfaction and beverage Sales through guest service excellence, cost-effective bar management and inventive cocktails
- Provided bar patrons with superior service and an enjoyable, memorable experience at Nashville Melting Pot
- Led a team of bartenders teaching advanced bar principles and techniques
- Excelled at up-selling guests from shelf to premium brands and high-margin signature cocktails.
- Helped drive average PPA (per-person average) increases of 15% and 17%
- Respectively leveraged interpersonal skills and drink-making knowledge to cultivate a loyal clientele
- Contributed to a 23% increase in weekday beverage sales and an 18% increase in weekend beverage sales at Melting Pot
- Reinvented classic cocktails, providing a new culinary spin on mojitos, manhattans, martinis
- Aided in training on improvements to bar inventory management, precision pouring and waste reduction. resulting in 5% decrease in liquor cost

OCT 2012 - JAN 2015 Server - Lead

- Took orders, presented and explained specials, offered information, and made suggestions about the menu.
- Up-sold wines, liquors, and five course meals with professional appearance and mannerism.
- Maintained clean and sanitary work areas and tables.
- Worked with servers as a team to execute 50+ person dining parties
- · Anticipated and fulfilled guest needs and requests.
- Memorized Fondue recipes and carefully crafted fondues for guests

- Followed proper plate presentation and garnished set up details.
- Served guests, prepared checks, and collected payment.

Server Assistant - Lead

MAY 2012 - OCT 2012

- Led team of four server assistants
- Organized and prepared services for special events
- Coordinated restaurant work flow with top management and servers
- Responsible for problem solving and special requests